" Chanting in ancient Javanese "
I 've looked into our accounting book .
Sales of your mother 's records already stopped .
no more royalty to be paid .
How about royalty from the previous years ?
They have been paid .
And for the past five years , no more profit .
How is your mom ?
Is she getting any better ?
You have no class today ?
I quit college .
Since when ?
Look , I can 't help much
Our financal situation isn 't too good now .
But Sir , I still see mom 's records in stores .
And radios still play her songs .
You still see them in stores because nobody buys them .
And you think radios pay to play songs ?
Your mom has been ill for more than 3 years .
She 's old .
She is not as popular as she once was .
Thank you , Sir .
Bondi 's school pants are torn again ?
I just sew them up last week .
He eats a lot .
Grows up fast .
You can 't retract your move .
One must learn to be calm .
How do you say ' don 't cheat 'in sign language ?
Don 't cheat .
How did it go , Rini ?
As we predicted , Dad .
No more royalty .
You shouldn 't have mortgaged this house .
How will you pay back ?
So what should have I done ?
All my savings are gone .
We needed to pay for your mom 's treatment .
You should have sold it .
We could 've bought a smaller house .
And paid mom 's medication with rest of the money .
How do you sell a house fast ?
You want your mom to die because I can 't pay for her treatment ?
Besides , this is your grandma 's house .
Not ours .
Go check on your mother .
Your mother .
Bondi , didn 't you hear mom 's ringing ?
Can 't you hear ?
That 's mother , Bondi .
Why are you afraid of her ?
Why isn 't mom in the hospital ?
Cause we got no more money to put her there .
So now we have to help Dad taking care of mother .
Mother ...
Did you pee ?
Are you hungry ?
SATAN 'S SLAVES
Mom , please come inside .
In a while .
Or your asthma will get worse .
It 's very late .
Where have you been ?
Just riding around .
So I won 't miss my bike .
Peace be upon thee ...
See , I 'm just right on time .
Tony , I 'm so sorry .
Don 't worry about it . We need the money .
How will you go to school tomorrow ?
Well , I can walk a bit .
Take a bus .
Walk some more .
Then take another bus .
You sure about this ?
Okay I change my mind then .
I 'll take it home now .
Thank you .
My religion class teacher said that during someone 's funeral
Forty steps after the last family member leave the funeral
the dead will wake up .
Why will he wake up ?
Just for a while .
When he realizes that he 's been wrapped in shroud
He dies again .
They have cameras inside graves ?
I put some in the cooking just now .
Put some more .
Delicious .
Salty .
Do you know
What will happen
If you put too much MSG in your food ?
What ?
You 'll grow long fangs .
You won 't be able to close your mouth .
I 'm not cooking that much food .
I thought you wouldn 't come home .
It 's alright . I had dinner .
I don 't liked your cooking anyway .
I 've brought some delicious beef with gravy .
Where did you get money from ?
Who says I need money ?
Where 's your watch ?
I misplaced it .
What else will you sell ?
I can sell my body .
Being a gigolo sounds fun .
What 's a gigolo ?
It 's a profession . Easy money .
They love you and they pay you .
I 'm gonna be a gigolo then .
Have you combed mom 's hair ?
I told you many times
She loves to have her hair combed before night falls .
I thought that 's your job .
Tony ...
Mother ...
Let me comb your hair .
Did you have your bath ?
You smell good already .
When you 're not sick anymore
If you decide to sing again
Let me be your guitar player .
I 'm very good now .
Mother , what 's wrong with your hair ?
Mother ...
Tomorrow I 'll find you something for your hair fall .
Have pity on the children .
Go sleep .
Mother ...
You can already stand up ?
MOTHER !
Daddy !
Your mother ...
She 's gone .
Mother .
" Islamic funeral prayer "
Thank you , Ustad for your help .
You are very welcome .
We 've never met before .
I just moved here with my son , Hendra .
His mom also passed away 10 years ago .
Sorry , I 've never seen your family in mosque .
We don 't pray , Ustad .
I 'm Hendra . Ustad 's son .
Hope to see you around .
Bondi what are you doing ?
They say ,
The last family member who walks 40 steps away from the grave
The dead one will wake up .
This is my 39th step .
That is not true . Let 's go .
What if Mom wakes up
and arises from the grave ?
So what 's your plan ?
Stay here till night time ?
And tomorrow and so on ?
There 's no god but Allah
Daddy
Can I skip school tomorrow ?
Why ?
You 're sick ?
Not really .
But we 're still mourning , right ?
We 've been mourning long time since mom fell ill .
Now mom 's at a better place .
She must be happy now .
So we shouldn 't be sad .
No need to mourn .
Now it 's time
To study harder .
Work harder .
So we can get more money .
Agree ?
Can Ian and I move to another room ?
What 's wrong ?
I can see the cemetery from the window .
There are only dead people in the cemetery .
Dead people are harmless .
The dangerous ones are the living .
Kidnappers .
Pickpockets .
Robbers .
Our family isn 't superstitious .
You shouldn 't be .
Sleep .
Your school pants torn again ?
Don 't worry , Dad . It 's a trend .
I 'll buy you a new pair .
No , I 'll look like a good kid .
Good kids get bullied .
Ok go to school in rags then .
Are you sad ?
Are you scared ?
You wanna sleep next to me ?
You 're scared , aren 't you ?
Silly ! Go sleep !
Isn 't it too soon ?
Mom just died yesterday .
Tomorrow you 're going out of town .
Our family needs can 't wait .
If I can 't raise money , bank will seize the house .
Take care of your brothers .
What if we need you ?
We can 't contact you .
Phone has been disconnected .
What will you need me for ?
I 'll be back as soon as possible .
You two are grown-ups now .
Ian ! Don 't scare me like that .
Look . There 's a zombie .
The zombie 's smart .
Can use flashlight .
Must be the caretaker of the cemetery .
Let 's go to bed .
Daddy 's gone ?
Yes .
Look who 's skipping school .
My friends will mock me if I go .
How come mom just died
And I go to school .
Smart ass .
Stingy ? Ok .
I want !
Tony .
Draw water from the well . Plumbing 's broken .
I 'm late !
Finish your food .
I will .
What ?
Hang on .
Takes forever .
Ok . Count 1 to 100 .
Then I 'll give you .
One ...
Two ...
Three ...
Four ...
Five ...
Seven ...
Eight ...
Nine ...
Ten ...
Ian ...
Tony ...
COMB MY HAIR !
I wanna pee .
Go pee .
Come with me ...
You asked me to accompany you .
Then you went alone .
What 's going on ?
Scary ...
What ?
Mother .
There 's a ghost !
Where ?
There 's no ghost .
Ian saw it too !
You 're imagining again .
Ian saw it !
Did you see ghost ?
No .
Bondi jumped on me .
I freaked out .
Mother .
These belong to you .
I bring them to you .
Please be at peace now .
During your mother 's funeral .
I saw something .
What ?
A woman .
Who ?
I guess she is one of the villagers .
That night I returned to your mom 's grave .
To sort things out .
I found nothing .
You got no fear ?
I was scared .
But I want to make sure your family is safe .
Unfortunately
What I was worried about happened .
Few days later I walked pass your house .
I saw her again .
What does she look like ?
Like your late mother .
You mean she looks like my mom
but she is someone else ?
I don 't think she is human .
So what do you think she is ?
Evil entity who has been living in someone 's body ...
Often imitate that person 's look .
You are a preacher 's son
Yet you believe in superstition .
My dad 's into religion .
I 'm more open-minded .
So what do you suggest ?
You guys should move out .
We may have to move out .
Bank may seize the house .
I mean sooner than that .
You guys can stay at our place .
Till your dad returns .
No , I don 't want to trouble you .
Not at all .
Thank you for your kindness .
But we 'll wait until Dad returns .
Grandma ?
Where is she ?
What ? !
She was drawing water from the well .
She slipped and fell into the well .
Careful , careful .
I apologize .
I asked you out for a walk .
And this happened .
How is he ?
His body temperature 's down .
He 's still shivering though .
He must be in shock .
Even I am .
Then I 'll give you .
To : Budiman Syailendra '
Hendra !
You said you wanted to help us .
Of course .
Take me downtown ?
Can I help you ?
My granma is Rahma Saidah . Before she died she wrote you this letter .
She didn 't mail it .
Alright thank you .
In the letter ,
she asked for your help to save us .
To save us from what ?
Your grandma has never taught you manners ?
Not to read someone else 's letter ?
I 'm so sorry .
Want to wait inside ?
Till I read this
So I 'll understand what the hell you 're talking about ?
I don 't want to .
Your grandma and I
were friends since primary school .
We were very close .
So close we never dated each other .
She ended up marrying my classmate .
They only got one son .
Your father .
When your dad married your mom
She never gave her blessings .
Why ?
Back then
Being an artist wasn 't considered dignified .
And it took so long for your mom to bear a child .
But my grandma and my mom were okay .
Yes after you were born .
But then
After your mom fell ill for years ,
Your grandma became suspicious .
Of what ?
She believed your mom ...
didn 't ask for children from God .
So from who ?
From Satan .
And you believe this ?
Your grandma believed it .
I don 't understand
about this Satan worship thing .
How do you do that ?
Isn 't this just fictious ?
If you believe so , why you come here ?
Something happened at home ?
I don 't want to .
Don 't want to kill my little brother .
I love my little brother .
I don 't want to .
I love my brother .
There 's my article in here .
Read it .
It might help you .
Time for your massage , Sir ?
You lost your specs again ?
I bought a new pair .
But people said they 're ugly .
You guys go .
I need my massage .
Please contact me if anything .
Who are you ?
I 'm Rini 's friend .
Bye .
They won 't be able to take any of you .
If you love each other .
Who are " they " ?
Read my article .
Why isn 't Bondi eating ?
He is .
But doesn 't want to eat with us .
Bondi .
Why are you eating by yourself ?
You 're still sick ?
Come eat with us .
Eat here .
Sit down .
From now on we got to stick together .
Take care of each other .
There 's nobody else but us .
Can I eat in front of TV ?
I ...
L ...
U.
I love you ...
You don 't have to wake up early .
Stay at home until you 're really ok .
I want ...
I want
you
... to die .
" Unintelligible words in reverse "
" Chanting in ancient language "
Where 's Ian ?
Did you see Ian ?
I just woke up .
Find him !
You know I 'll always be here for you , right ?
So will Tony .
And Bondi .
Where did you get this from ?
A friend of Granma 's . I met him yesterday .
Have you read it ?
What for ?
Just a stupid magazine about the occult .
What ?
" EXPOSING THE DEVIL WORSHIP FERTILITY CULT "
It tells story of a woman
who 's been married for 10 years and cannot have a child .
and finally gave birth to a child .
By asking from Satan , in a cave ...
or in a sacred mountain .
No .
Not in a cave or mountain .
This article says , in cities there are satan-worshipping cults ...
which are related to fertility .
What does it mean ?
Someone who wishes to have a child ...
but barren
They can join the cult
Then they 'll get pregnant .
Well that 's good , right .
As long as they can have a child .
But
However , the last child
must be given to the cult to be sacrificed
when he reaches 7 years old .
So what 's point of having it then ?
Well , only the last child .
When he reaches 7 years old .
So what 's your point ?
Okay .
How old are you ?
Twenty two .
I 'm sixteen .
and Bondi is ten .
And ?
What if Mom didn 't have the heart to give us to that cult
so before her last child reaches 7 years old
Mom always had a new baby .
You know nobody takes this magazine seriously , right ?
Do you remember
When Mom still performed
I always accompanied her .
Yeah I hate attending those and socializing .
Everytime she had an event
There were always a group of people
Never mingled with others
But they were always there .
This is them .
This one .
And this one .
Perhaps mom 's schoolmates ?
Once I asked them myself
They kept their mouth shut .
The last child
Seven years old .
Ian turns seven in three days .
But the article says
The child can only be taken
if his family gives him up .
Taken how ?
That 's the part that I don 't believe .
What does it say ?
It says that the promised child
will be taken by ...
the living dead .
Good thing it says that . I 'm so relieved .
If it says they will kidnap him , maybe I would believe it .
Could be a metaphor , an analogy .
I 'm hungry .
Stop reading this trash .
Or you 'll go cuckoo .
You sure you saw her ?
I 'm sure , Ustad .
Your grandma ?
Grandma .
Show me your mother 's room .
Dead people don 't bother the living .
They 're usually other beings
imitating the ones you love
to tear your family apart .
Is it safe now ?
I can only ask for help from God .
So nothing will disturb you again .
Thank you for your help , Ustad .
Do you pray ?
We don 't .
But you know how ?
We do .
Then pray .
Pray before Allah
surrender whole heartedly
to Allah almighty .
Because all beings are afraid of Him .
If you pray but not whole heartedly
you 'll still be vulnerable .
Ustad , can we ...
Get in .
We shouldn 't have run away .
If that really was Mother .
We ask her not to disturb us anymore .
That wasn 't mom .
A Jinn ?
There are other beings beside humans and djinns .
They 've been around before religions existed .
What do they want from humans ?
Harvesting human souls that they plant .
Is there a way to defeat them ?
According to the article ,
we can 't defeat them .
But we can disobey their rules .
What do you mean ?
They won 't be able to take a child
Unless he 's given up by his family .
So we just have to stick together .
Let me get that .
Sister ,
There 's something else in the magazine .
What ?
Women in that cult
weren 't impregnated by their husbands .
So by whom ?
by the men in the cult .
You 're saying ...
You ever think
why the four of us look very different from each other ?
Many siblings don 't look alike .
Not like us .
Budiman called .
Something important came up .
But I have to look after my brothers
Let me go there .
I 'll go with you .
No need .
But I need to know .
Look after your sister and the little ones .
You sure ?
Of course .
I 'll go straight home afterwards .
See you soon .
We 'll hold a mass prayer at your house
We 'll invite the villagers
Thank you , Ustad .
Sorry for giving you trouble .
Not at all .
Houses in which the inhibitants don 't pray
will be easily occupied by Satan
It will be hard to get rid of it .
Where 's Rini ?
She 's looking after her brothers
I can take your message to her .
This is my latest article .
If we wait until it 's published it will be too late
Too late for what ?
Give this to Rini .
Rini is my friend . I 'm helping her .
Please tell me what 's going on .
Where 's that knife ?
Oh here it is .
Lucky you didn 't get cut .
Who 's that ?
Massage , Sir .
Didn 't I say later tonight ?
I can 't tonight .
Open this door , Sir .
Ustad . Peace be upon thee .
Sir ...
Daddy !
I got home , you weren 't there .
What are you doing here ?
Many things happened while you 're gone .
Let 's go home .
Tomorrow we pack things up .
Take only what we need .
We move to a flat downtown .
Now go to bed .
Get up early .
I apoligize for leaving you guys .
You should but not just for that .
I saw you speak to mom the night she died .
What did you say to her ?
I meant well .
I want happiness for my kids .
And your mom to find peace .
What did you say to her ?
I love my children .
And I love your mother .
But I think
my children should not to suffer
You gave up on her .
Ian !
Dad !
Dad ! Help !
What happened ? !
Someone locked Ian in !
Ian !
Step aside !
Dad ... Dad ...
Throw down the rope !
Grab this .
Pull hard !
Take Ian first !
Take Ian !
Who are they ?
Definitely not our neighbors .
What the hell do you want from us ? !
Rini get inside !
Get inside !
Watch over your brother .
They 're surrounding us .
What are they doing ?
They come to take Ian .
They can 't as long as we don 't let them .
Bondi ... Bondi ...
I love you ...
Mother ! Please help my children .
Bondi ... Bondi ...
Mawarni ...
Please save our children .
Bondi ...
This is my fault .
Forgive me .
Bondi ... I love you ...
Daddy !
Are you hurt ?
You can 't take any of my children !
We won 't let you !
If you still dare to do so
Come forward !
Fight me !
Dad get inside !
They 're gone . They 're all gone .
What time will the car arrive ?
4 P.M.
Dad , you sure you have money for rent ?
God willing .
And if I work hard enough
I 'll be able to pay back the house .
I don 't think you should do that .
Well , I won 't then .
Better buy a small house , but lots of neighbors .
Okay , let 's just leave the furnitures .
We 'll buy new ones
I 'm super loaded now . Filthy rich .
Can you believe that ?
You can 't ? Neither can I.
When we reach downtown ,
We drop our stuffs , then we go out
We 'll celebrate Ian 's birthday at midnight .
That must be our ride .
Oh hi , Ustad .
Peace be upon thee .
I heard you 're moving out .
I came to wish you a good journey .
Thank you .
I 'm going for a walk .
Please .
Thank you for taking care of the kids
Forgive me for not able to help last night .
To be honest ,
I 'm still in shock .
My deepest condolences
Please regard my kids as yours
I appreciate that .
Ustad , something to drink ?
Thank you .
- What about you , Dad ? - Tea , please .
If I had a car ,
I would 've taken you downtown .
Don 't worry about it .
Our ride must 've had some engine problem .
It 's 10.30 . We should just go to bed .
Ian will have his birthday at midnight .
We can set the alarm for midnight .
You guys have been packing since morning .
If it 's okay , can I stay here for a while ?
I feel so lonely at home .
Of course it 's okay .
You guys go to bed . I 'll wake you up later .
Haven 't we paid the electricity bill ?
I think it 's a general blackout .
Let me get the kerosene lights .
Let 's go , Tony .
" Satan 's Grand Plan to Spread His Seeds ' By : Budiman Syailendra "
Tony , wake up .
Has the birthday party started ?
Have you ever been haunted by grandma 's ghost ?
No .
I haven 't . Neither has Bondi .
Only Ian has been haunted .
So ?
This is Budiman 's new article . Apparently he gave it to Hendra .
This one revises the previous article .
What does it revise ?
The last child from the cult
will be taken not as a sacrifice .
But because they 're Satan 's offsprings .
What if grandma was trying to help us all along ?
Sister ,
Listen to yourself . This is nuts .
Ian is our little brother . We take care of him since baby .
There 's something else .
Tell me .
The cult members don 't come to the house , not to take the Satan 's child .
But to leave signs for his shepherds .
Who are the shepherds ?
It 's mother .
" Talking in ancient language "
Ian , what are you doing ?
Talking to my friends .
Hendra ...
Mawarni ...
Your brothers .
Ustad ...
Dad .
Where 's Ian ?
What the hell is going on ? Where 's Ian ?
- What do we do now ? - We stay here .
We have to find Ian . No don 't .
What 's with you ? Your brother is out there !
Step aside .
Ian !
Ian ?
Come here , Daddy .
Dad get inside .
Granma !
Rini !
Come quick !
Drive now , please !
C 'mon , c 'mon !
Let 's go !
Quickly !
They 're getting close !
NOW ! NOW !
Ian !
He 's not your son .
He 's never been .
" ONE YEAR LATER "
Hi , I bring you some food .
I cooked too much .
Thank you so much .
We only have eggs today .
Just ask if you need more food .
Thank you .
You 're very welcome .
Close the door .
Did you give them the food ?
I did .
Those poor children .
We have to make sure they don 't move out .
It 's time for another harvest .
Be patient , Darminah .